# Lisa Orr, PhD

Portland, Oregon | Linkedin

Product leader with 9 years of experience, building high-value solutions and driving adoption through discovery and experimentation. Background in data science and experience building and launching predictive solutions. Demonstrated experience leading product discovery trios and shipping competitive and customer-loved solutions.

# Professional Experience

#### 2022

# Senior Product Manager, Advocates for Human Potential

Managed a team of four including product managers and product analysts. Established continuous discovery and agile development processes including roadmapping, team onboarding, and opportunity solution trees.

Led the product discovery and development for the Behavioral Health Response and Rescue Project facilitating the distribution of \$3 billion in funding to private and county level programs to solve the homelessness crisis. Collaborated with data analytics and engineering to design the grant application administration platform.

#### 2021 - 2022

# Senior Product Manager, Human API

Product manager for the Real Time Health Identity and Life Sciences verticals representing 2.3M ARR for 25 customers and 170k end users. Created the market-first vaccine search experience platform facilitating 10k+ weekly users connecting their digital vaccine records.

Led the product discovery and development of the Life Sciences Patient Activation Experience. Discovery included the evaluation, selection, and integration of 3rd party solutions for ID verification, electronic documentation signature, and provider search.

Led engineering, sales, and customer success teams in developing a cohesive product vision, roadmap, and delivery timeline to drive company business initiatives.

## 2019 - 2021

# Senior Product Manager · Lead Product Manager, Airship

Product Manager for the Orchestration solution, representing 25M ARR with 80

# Lisa Orr, PhD

Portland, Oregon | Linkedin

customers and 10M+ end users. Led a team of 9 and together we won "Product Team of the Year" in 2021 competing with 4 other product teams. Authored and granted a US patent for cross channel orchestration innovations, Patent Number 11050699.

Shipped Airship Journeys, a major strategic initiative to uplevel personalization capabilities including an A/B testing suite. Journeys drove 3.5MM in revenue in the first 6 months of launch through new sales and customer upgrades, many being initial beta testers of the product. Presented product work to the Airship Board of Directors. Journeys was key in Airship attaining "Leader" status for Gartner's 2020 Magic Quadrant for Mobile Marketing Platforms.

Led sales and customers success teams to build a customer discovery platform to drive product adoption, improve the product based on customer feedback, and derive customer testimonials in support of product launches.

#### 2015 - 2019

## Data Scientist · Senior Data Scientist · Lead Data Scientist, Airship

Built machine learning models to optimize digital engagement automation. Work included feature engineering with MapReduce, model exploration with and evaluation with Python processing ~30TB compressed data.

Built and launched two predictive solutions including Predictive Send Time Optimization, which increased user response rate by up to 14%. Presented data science work to the Airship Board of Directors. Authored and granted a US patent for churn prediction innovations, Patent Number 11232465.

## Education

#### 2014

# PhD in Cognitive Psychology, University of St. Andrews

Led research on the evolution of human language through studies of our closest living ancestors, Bonobos (*Pan paniscus*), and their use of gestures to convey meaning.

## 2007

BS in Ecology and Evolutionary Biology, University of California at Santa Cruz

# Lisa Orr, PhD

Portland, Oregon | Linkedin

# Accomplishments and Acknowledgements

- Fulbright Scholarship University of Lund, Sweden, 2008-2009
- Graduate Research Fellowship, National Science Foundation, 2010-2014
- Created and taught a Data Science Workshop through Women Who Code
- Created, ran, and participated as a mentor in Airship's Co-Pilot Mentorship Program

# Select Media

### Authored

- Human API, 2021. <u>Live Internal Product Testing: How we used our very own COVID</u> vaccine and test results product at our company retreat!
- Airship, 2020. <u>How brands are improving conversion rates using Airship Journeys optimization</u>
- Linkedin, 2020. *How to build a mentorship program*
- Github, 2019. *Machine Learning Workshop*: Self-contained workshop materials including slides, jupyter notebook exercises, cheat sheets and Readme overview
- Inside Big Data. 2017. <u>Predicting Mobile App User Churn: Training & Scaling Our Machine Learning Model</u>

## **Featured**

- Product Talk, 2021 <u>Product in Practice: Finding the Best Way to Communicate with Different Stakeholders</u>
- Product Talk, 2020. <u>Product in Practice: Tackling Big Hairy Product Challenges with Continuous Discovery</u>

### **Patents**

- US Patent and Trademark Office, 2020. Cross channel orchestration of messages
- US Patent and Trademark Office, 2017. Churn prediction with machine learning